https://nirsa.net/nirsa/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy – NIRSA
Skip to content
NIRSA NIRSA Canadian RegionNIRSA Region INIRSA Region IINIRSA Region IIINIRSA Region IVNIRSA Region VNIRSA Region VIAbout Contact NIRSA HeadquartersCalendarBluefishJobs Virtual Career Week: April 20-24Partner with UsDonateLogin
FacebookTwitterYouTubeInstagramPinterestEmailNIRSA Connect
Grow Grow your career in campus recreationEvents & OpportunitiesNEW!NIRSA Annual Conference Past NIRSA ConferencesRegional Events Resources for Event OrganizersNIRSA Event ServicesCore CompetenciesRCRSP Apply/RenewApplication CriteriaNIRSA CEU ProvidersStandards of ConductList of Registered ProfessionalsPresenter InformationDiscover Discover the possibilities in campus recreationCoronavirus Updates & ResourcesResearch & AssessmentPublicationsStudent ResourcesRec Day – February 22Member Discounts & RewardsNews NIRSA Know NewsletterConnect Get connected with your campus rec networkNIRSA ConnectRegional, State, and Provincial NetworksMember Directory Find an IndividualFind an InstitutionBuyer’s GuideRecChat@NIRSALive Social MediaNIRSA Ideas in Motion: Virtual RoundtablesLead Lead campus recreation through volunteeringNIRSA Leadership NIRSA Board of DirectorsNIRSA Member NetworkNIRSA AssemblyVolunteer GroupsGet InvolvedNIRSA ElectionsStrategic Values Leadership in Campus RecreationSustainability in Campus RecreationHealth & Wellbeing ResourcesAwards & ScholarshipsNIRSA Foundation DonateLeave a LegacyBoard of DirectorsCorporate Partners#GivingTuesdayYear in ReviewNIRSA Services Corporation Board of DirectorsPlay NIRSA Championship SeriesBasketballFlag FootballSoccerTennisOfficials DevelopmentIntramural Sport RulesJoin Become a leader in collegiate recreationMember DiscountsMember Benefits Associate Member Benefits
Search for:
AboutScheduleFacultyHotel & TravelRegistrationSponsorship
Search for:
Privacy PolicyCory Granholm2019-07-10T21:02:30-07:00
Privacy PolicyNIRSA is committed to protecting the privacy and personal data of our members and those that use NIRSA products and services. This Privacy Policy explains what type of personal information is collected by NIRSA (“we”, or “us”) and how we use that information. It applies to data shared online, stored in our computer system or in hard copy. Our commitment to data security is important to us and this policy has been reviewed to comply with strengthened data privacy protection rules across the EU, under the General Data Protection Regulation, Canada and in the United States.
About Us
NIRSA is an advocate for the advancement of recreation, sport, and wellbeing in higher education. As a membership organization, our focus is on providing resources, networking, and professional development that support the advancement of the campus recreation profession.
NIRSA is the data controller and processor of the personal information that you provide to us as a member, as part of the NIRSA Connect community, or when you access our services, trainings, or events. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, how to manage the use of your personal data or to remove your data from our records, you can contact us at:
NIRSA Data Protection Lead4185 SW Research Way Corvallis, Oregon 97333-1067Phone: 541-766-8211Fax: 541-766-8284Email: privacy@nirsa.orgWeb: www.nirsa.org
What Personally Identifiable Information Is Collected by NIRSAThe personal information, in any format, that we collect and hold, is handled in accordance with this Policy. Where we ask you to provide information by which you can be identified when visiting our website, or using any NIRSA services, you can be assured that this Policy applies. We will always explain clearly what data we are collecting about you and for what purpose. We only collect data to provide you with a better experience, to improve and deliver services to you, to meet our legitimate interests as a membership organization, and to comply with our legal responsibilities.
Individuals who sign up for membership, register for an event or create a NIRSA profile provide us with contact and demographic information via their online profile or through print or online application or registration forms. Your name, address, email, and highest academic degree are used for communicating NIRSA benefits to you (such as to email you a receipt or mail you a membership resources packet). You may opt out of non-transactional emails at any time if you do not wish to receive informational or promotional messages from NIRSA. Any banking details collected by NIRSA are solely used for transactional purposes.
All other demographic information that NIRSA collects via online profiles or surveys is shared at the individual’s discretion. All personal data of NIRSA members and users is stored on a secure server. Data is retained for the life-cycle of the NIRSA Connect online community and while you are a member of NIRSA. We may be required to retain personal data after your membership expires for legal or other legitimate business purposes. This may include retention of personal information that may be necessary to meet our contractual obligations to you, to identify issues, or to resolve legal proceedings. We may also retain aggregate information beyond this time for research purposes and to help us develop and improve our services. You cannot be identified from aggregate information retained or used for these purposes. These practices align with legislation and guidelines on retention of personal data.
NIRSA follows standard document retention policies which are posted on the NIRSA website.
What NIRSA Does with the Information we CollectNIRSA advocates for our members and strives to provide benefits and resources to advance the campus recreation profession. The lawful basis for processing personal data is by consent, legitimate interest, and to meet legal responsibilities. Gender, ethnicity, and salary data – while all optional for users to provide – helps us to forecast trends in the industry and tailor the development of future benefits to better meet members’ needs.
No personally identifiable data is shared with non-member groups or individuals without your advance consent. You have the right to control the use of your personal data. You can delete demographic and contact data from your NIRSA profile and NIRSA Connect profile at any time. Mailing addresses of members are provided to associate members upon request. You may opt out of any or all non-transactional NIRSA communication services through adjusting your communication preferences on your NIRSA profile at www.nirsa.me
EmailsEmail addresses are used for official NIRSA business only and are not shared with other companies, including Associate Members, without your permission. NIRSA event registrants may also opt-in to share their email addresses with companies who are exhibiting at the same event for the express purpose of receiving promotional emails from exhibitors.
NIRSA ConnectThe Association’s online networking platform makes discussion boards and document sharing available to users. It also contains the NIRSA member directory. All individual NIRSA members are automatically added to the NIRSA Discussion Group upon joining or renewing. You may edit your discussion group email preferences and your Connect Profile privacy settings at any time. You can also adjust what profile information is viewable by others in the Member Directory. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in NIRSA Connect is viewable to all members and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. You may opt out of the NIRSA Connect platform, adjust your communication settings, and edit your Connect profile by visiting www.nirsa.me.
CookiesA cookie is a small data text file that is placed in your browser and allows us to recognize you each time you visit the NIRSA website (personalization, etc). Cookies themselves do not contain any personal information, and we do not use cookies to collect personal information. Cookies may also be used by third party content providers such as newsfeeds. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify the settings of most browsers to decline cookies. Declining cookies may prevent you from taking full advantage of the NIRSA website.
External Links to Other SitesThe NIRSA website contains links to other internet sites external to the NIRSA domain. NIRSA is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of external websites. NIRSA does not have any control over other websites. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide while visiting external sites and such sites are not governed by this Privacy Policy. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
NIRSA Service ProvidersWe may share your personal information with companies (including NIRSA affiliates) in order that those companies can perform services on our behalf; for example, electronic banking companies that help process credit card payments. Our service providers are required by contract to protect the confidentiality of the personal information we share with them and to use it exclusively to provide specific services on our behalf.
Legal DisclosuresWe may disclose the personal information we collect through the NIRSA website, when we, in good faith, believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law (or a court order or subpoena); to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft; to enforce the Association’s Terms and Conditions or other agreements that govern the use of this site; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of the company, its users, or others.
Review of This PolicyNIRSA conducts regular reviews of this Privacy Policy to ensure compliance with current regulations and ensure care of personal data. You are encouraged to occasionally revisit this policy to ensure that you are aware of any changes. The NIRSA Privacy Policy was last updated in October 2018.
Our Mission NIRSA is a leader in higher education and the advocate for the advancement of recreation, sport, and wellbeing.
Web:
nirsa.org
Search the NIRSA Website
Search for:
©2013-2020 NIRSA: Leaders in Collegiate Recreation | All Rights Reserved | Terms & Conditions | Privacy Policy
Go to Top
